



#### **RESEARCH FOCUS**

My research explores the intersection of Human-Computer Interaction (HCI), Artificial Intelligence (AI), and User Experience (UX). I design, evaluate, and improve human-AI collaborative tools to support usability and UX analysis.

I also collaborate with other researchers on topics including accessibility in computing education, accessible technology for older adults, and VR for older adults.

## **EDUCATION**

## PhD in Computing and Information Sciences

Aug 2020 - present

Rochester Institute of Technology, New York State, United States Advised by Dr. Kristen Shinohara and Dr. Mingming Fan Participating in the AWARE-AI NSF Research Traineeship (NRT) Program

## **BASc in Biomedical Engineering**

Sept 2015 - Apr 2020

University of Waterloo, Ontario, Canada Capstone advised by Dr. John Zelek Graduated on Dean's Honour List

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## **Rochester Institute of Technology**

Aug 2020 - present

Graduate Research Assistant

- Conduct HCI research focused on the human-centered design of AI-powered technologies, including visual analytics tools and conversational assistants to support UX analysis
- Design, conduct, and analyze research studies employing a variety of methods including interviews, surveys, design probes, usability studies, and quantitative experiments
- Author technical papers for publication and develop dissemination plans

## Meta, Reality Labs

May 2022 - Aug 2022

UX Research Intern

- Conducted literature review and authored reports on first-hand experiences to inform the design of an AR hardware prototype
- Designed and conducted a user study with 30 participants to investigate audio performance
- Presented results to >100 product stakeholders including researchers, engineers, and cross-functional partners; recommendations led to changes in product design

Last Updated: Oct 2022

#### Uncharted Software Inc., ASKE-E Team

May 2021 - Aug 2021

Research Intern

- Worked on the DARPA Automating Scientific Knowledge Extraction (ASKE) program
- Designed wireframes and implemented new features in the human-machine interface (HMI) of a visual analytics system for multi-scale graph analysis and knowledge discovery [W.1]

**Huawei Technologies Canada, Human-Machine Interaction (HMI) Lab**Jan 2019 - Aug 2020

Research Engineer

- Trained machine learning models for gesture recognition using Tensorflow
- Designed and conducted user experiments to explore novel interaction techniques on large screens using mid-air gesture input; presented in the Huawei Developer Conference 2019

# University of Waterloo, Vision and Image Processing (VIP) Lab

May 2016 - Apr 2018

Research Assistant

- Designed and 3D-printed a lens-free microscope [J.2] and a smartphone spectrometer [J.1]
- Conducted testing with biological specimens to achieve optical resolution in the nm range

## PEER-REVIEWED JOURNAL PUBLICATIONS

- J.3 Ehsan Jahangirzadeh Soure\*, **Emily Kuang\***, Mingming Fan, and Jian Zhao. CoUX: Collaborative Visual Analysis of Think-Aloud Usability Test Videos for Digital Interfaces. IEEE Transactions on Visualizations and Computer Graphics (TVCG), (Proc. of IEEE VIS), 2021. DOI: 10.1109/TVCG.2021.3114822 (\* denotes equal contribution)
- J.2 **Emily Kuang**, Farnoud Kazemzadeh, Alexander Wong. Enhanced Smartphone Spectroscopy via High-throughput Computational Slit. *Journal of Computational Vision and Imaging Systems*, vol. 2, no. 1, 2016. DOI: 10.15353/vsnl.v2i1.97
- J.1 Farnoud Kazemzadeh, **Emily Kuang**, Alexander Wong. Compact, Field-Portable Lens-free Microscope using Superresolution Spatio-Spectral Light-field Fusion. Journal of Computational Vision and Imaging Systems, vol. 2, no. 1, 2016. DOI: 10.15353/vsnl.v2i1.105

## PEER-REVIEWED CONFERENCE PUBLICATIONS

C.3 **Emily Kuang**, Xiaofu Jin, Mingming Fan. "Merging Results Is No Easy Task": An International Survey Study of Collaborative Data Analysis Practices Among UX Practitioners. Proc. ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI), 2022.

DOI: 10.1145/3491102.3517647

- C.2 Xiaofu Jin, **Emily Kuang**, Mingming Fan. "Too old to bank digitally?": A Survey of Banking Practices and Challenges Among Older Adults in China. Proc. ACM Conference on Designing Interactive Systems (DIS), 2021. DOI: 10.1145/3461778.3462127
- C.1 Ameneh Boroomand, Mohammad Javad Sahfiee, Linda Wang, **Emily Kuang**, Farnoud Kazemzadeh, Alexander Wong. Compensated lens-free light field spectroscopy. Proc. International Conference on Inverse Problems in Engineering (ICIPE), 2017.

## PEER-REVIEWED WORKSHOP PUBLICATIONS

W.1 Fahd Husain, Rosa Romero-Gómez, **Emily Kuang**, Dario Segura, Adamo Carolli, Lai Chung Liu, Manfred Cheung, Yohann Paris. A Multi-scale Visual Analytics Approach for Exploring Biomedical Knowledge. Proc. Workshop on Visual Analytics in Healthcare (VAHC), IEEE VIS, 2021. arXiv:2109.06828 ▼Best Paper Winner]

## **INVITED TALKS & POSTERS**

## Human-AI Collaboration for UX Evaluation: Visualizations and Conversationals Assistants

• Poster presentation at RIT Artificial Intelligence Summit, Oct 2022

#### Crafting Human-AI Collaborative Analysis of Usability Test Recordings

Poster presentation at CRA-WP Grad Cohort for Women, Apr 2022

#### Collaborative Visual Analysis of Think-Aloud Usability Test Videos for Digital Interfaces

• Guest Lecture in ISTE782: Visual Analytics, Nov 2021

#### **AWARDS AND HONORS**

Department Nomination for Google Ph.D. Fellowship ~ RIT	2022
Department Nomination for Microsoft Research Ph.D. Fellowship $\sim RIT$	2022
Merit-based Ph.D. Scholarship ~ RIT	2020
<b>Experience Award</b> ~ Natural Sciences and Engineering Research Council of Canada (NSERC)	2018
President's Research Award ~ University of Waterloo	2018
President's Research Award ~ University of Waterloo	2017
Undergraduate Student Research Award ~ NSERC	2016
President's Scholarship of Distinction ~ University of Waterloo	2015

Last Updated: Oct 2022

## **PROFESSIONAL SERVICE**

#### **Paper Reviewer**

ACM CHI 2023 Full papersACM CHI 2022 Full papers

• **Chinese CHI** 2021 Late Breaking Work

#### **Student Volunteer**

• ACM CHI 2022 New Orleans, LA, USA

• **IEEE VIS** 2021 Remote

## **Council Representative**

• AWARE-AI NSF Research Traineeship 2022-2023

#### **Project Judge**

• GENIUS Olympiad 2022: International Project Competition

#### ADDITIONAL PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## North Inc. (now acquired by Google)

Apr 2018 - Aug 2018

Computer Vision Developer

- Designed algorithm to quantify image sharpness and created a GUI to output real-time metrics; reduced time needed for assembling multi-camera system used to fit smart glasses
- Conducted field studies on the sizing procedure; results led to process improvements

#### Synaptive Medical Inc.

Sept 2017- Dec 2017

Optics Engineering Intern

- Designed and led an investigation into the stabilization of stereoscopic videos for a neurosurgical robot; results led to reduced complexity of the FPGA architecture
- Collected feedback from surgeons to optimize visualization presets during mock surgeries

#### St. Michael's Hospital

Jan 2017 - Apr 2017

Medical Imaging Research Assistant

- Created a video processing pipeline for non-invasive detection of diabetic foot ulcers
- Assisted with patient interviews to determine user requirements for the in-home prototype